Satheesh Natarajan

satheeshnatarajan@outlook.com Holding US B1 VISA - Valid till 2030 +91 9698480404

Summary

As a Full Stack Developer I have 5.7 years of experience in Web Application Development, Project Execution and Application maintenance. Experienced in single page application development with responsive design. Having a knowledge of NodeJs with its most popular libraries.

Technical Abilities

Programming languages - JavaScript

Libraries & Frameworks - Node Js, Express Js, React Js, Redux, Angular Js, jQuery, Webpack, Sequelize, Adobe Analytics (omniture), nglnx, Masterpass, Visa Checkout, Mercury, Authorize.Net Payment Gateway

Markup & Styles - HTML, CSS, SCSS

Others - Source Control (Git), Agile Tracking (JIRA), Documentation (Confluence)

Education

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering

2014

Mount Zion College of Engineering and Technology

Professional Experience - 5.7 Yrs

Full Stack Developer - Echidna / Kloud9

(Nov, 2017 - Present)

Kohls - https://m.kohls.com, https://mobile.kohls.com Nov, 2017 - Present

- Ecommerce website, one of the most largest department stores by retail sales in the united states
- All google indexing page like home, pmp and pdp are developed in react with server side rendering and checkout flow were developed in angularjs
- Developed HTML and business logic for both mobile and tablet site in common code based on the visual design
- My Role in the project, would implement the each new module for each month release with support till to the production
- Implemented the adobe analytics (omniture) for tracking a client activities

• Technologies used in the project were reactjs, angularjs, angular 4, omniture, jQuery, webpack, nodejs, spring boot

MTS - Level1 - Nexii IT Labs Pvt Ltd

(Jan, 2017 - Sep, 2017)

Cloud File Vault, Jul 2017 – Sep 2017

- Cloud File Vault is a product for taking backup from the local file system to cloud storage. Regular backup to sync the local and cloud files with trace history
- Role in the Project, design and functional implementation the application flow as the UX design
- Used Angular 4 framework for single page driven application

RSA Netwitness Platform | Cloud Computing Management, Dell EMC | Jan 2017 – July 2017

- The RSA Enterprise Compromise Assessment Tool (RSA Netwitness Platform) product is an endpoint threat detection solution that exposes malware and other threats, highlights suspicious activity for investigation, and instantly determines the scope of a compromise to help security teams stop advanced threats faster.
- RSA Netwitness Platform's unique signature-less approach identifies known, as well as previously unknown threats that other solutions miss.
- Role in the Project, develop UI as per UX design with functional flow
- Maintain code coverage with unit test cases of all business logic
- Used Ember.js, Ember Redux frameworks

Software Engineer - Nyqmind

(Sep, 2014 - Jan, 2017)

IQOS Web Application - http://544food.com, SPF Solutions LLC Feb 2015 – Jun 2015

- Online food ordering web application for Aspen and Denver locations in the United States. Updating a live status of ordered food in the application.
- Each restaurant having a different cuisines with menus
- Developed the site from scratch, being a lead developer with team size of two people

- Used angularjs for maintaining the single page application and with the help of custom Gulp script to bundle the project with minified and chunks
- Integrated payment gateway system with the web application Mercury, Authorize.Net Payment

Swanstrom Staffing, Swanstrom Company Jul 2015 – Aug 2015

- The project entails contractor availability information captured by the project lead to be stored in a central location. This information would be later accessed by the S.O.S agent for updating status followed by the status to be received by Project Lead
- Developed from scratch and being a lead developer both the front and back end of this application
- Used angularJs and Spring Boot with Hibernate ORM

TSpoon, Sep 2015 – Aug 2016

- TSpoon app helps families to create customized meal plans quickly and conveniently. Based on your family's health profile, you can create a plan for up to 7 days. And you can also get customized meal plans from your Nutritionist according to your health profile.
- Developed from scratch and being a lead developer for the front end application
- Used angularJs with integration of Angular Material

IQOS Order Management System, SPF Solutions LLC

- A backend for IQOS Online Food ordering application which builds on Spring MVC,
 Hibernate ORM with MySQL database connectivity.
- More secured Restful API service for Mobile and Web application
- Role of the project, Maintain the orders, offers, menus, pickup/delivery maintenance and some other features.
- Implemented new features such as address validation, pricing with Code maintenance and bug fixes